BRUNO I. GARCIA GONZALEZ









Driven software developer of 1.5+ years, including over a year of teaching JavaScript (ES6), ReactJS, and Ruby on Rails (as both a full stack and API framework). Lifelong student who excels at building workplace cohesion through strong communication skills and positive energy, and can fit well within various team dynamics.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Flatiron School, Washington, DC

Lead Instructor In-Training, August 2019 - Present

- + Deliver lectures to 40+ students, and counting.
- + Lecture topics include: HTTP REST MVC Framework Ruby on Rails JavaScript (ES6) ReactJS.
- + Make decisions about students' advancement through the Program, by assessing performance.

Flatiron School, Washington, DC

Software Engineering Coach, August 2018 - August 2019

- + Coached 30+ students extensively and worked with dozens more directly (1:1 and leading groups).
- + Led/Co-Led three (3) "Intro To Front End Development" workshops, teaching HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- + Developed a "Coaches' Onboarding Manual" to help the company with its scaling.

Conservation International & International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN), Arlington, VA

Intern with the joint-organization Biodiversity Assessment Unit, June 2017 - December 2017

- + Contributor to and Compiler of 200-400 species accounts for The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species.
- + Conducted literature reviews, compiled species information, and created species distribution maps (ArcGIS Software Suite).
- + Focused on Southeast Asian Herpetofauna & Andean crop wild relatives.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: • JavaScript • Ruby

Frameworks: • ReactJS (& Redux) • Jest + Enzyme • Ruby on Rails (API & Full-stack) • Sinatra (a Ruby DSL) • RSpec

Databases: • PostgreSQL • SQLite

Other: • Object-Oriented Programming • HTTP • WebSockets • REST • MVC Architecture • Test-writing

Tools: • Agile Development • Git • GitHub

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

LinkShare - video demo | front end code | back end code

A people's directory for community-based internet mapping and exploration

- + Built a ReactJS application fed by a custom Ruby on Rails API
- + Employed PostgreSQL as the API's database manager (RDBMS)
- + Leveraged BCrypt hashing for user data security
- + Utilized ChartJS for data visualization

WeatherScript - video demo | all code

An elegant weather app, similar to Apple's Weather app

- + Built a ReactJS application fed by a custom Ruby on Rails API
- + Employed MetaWeather API to integrate up-to-date weather data

CryptoHome - front end code | back end code

A new homepage for cryptocurrency fans

- + Built a Single Page Application (SPA) by leveraging JavaScript Promises (AJAX)
- + Employed SocketIO and the CryptoCompare API to integrate real-time price ticker (WebSockets)
- + Leveraged Rails ActionCable to integrate a real-time chat feature (WebSockets)
- + Utilized PlotlyJS for data visualization

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - 2018

+ Full Stack Web Development, Immersive Program (Ruby/Rails & JavaScript/ReactJS/Redux & PostgreSQL)

University of Maryland - College Park, MD - 2015

+ Bachelor of Science, Plant Sciences